bhat.ashwin03@gmail.com \* 305-878-1762 \* linkedin.com/in/abhat4 \* theshwin.com

## **ABOUT**

I recently graduated from Johns Hopkins University with my Bachelor of Science in computer engineering. I also minored in robotics, computer science, and applied math/statistics. I am primarily interested in opportunities in engineering to gain experience with real-world applications. I enjoy working with robots and computers and conducting research. From my previous work, I have learned how to tackle challenging problems and find solutions to them.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Johns Hopkins University

August 2014 - May 2018

#### Whiting School of Engineering

Major: Computer Engineering; Minors: Robotics, Applied Math and Statistics, and Computer Science Dean's List

- Robotics Club
- Institute of Electrical & Electronics Engineers (Vice President)
- Association for Computing Machinery

#### John A. Ferguson Senior High School

August 2010 - June 2014

## International Baccalaureate Diploma Program, GPA: 4.000, 8.033 (weighted)

• Top 1% of class, Summa Cum Laude, earned the IB Diploma and AP Scholar with Distinction

# **SKILLS**

Programming Languages

Programming Skills
Engineering Skills

Selected Coursework
Other Skills

C, C++, Python, Matlab, VHDL, Java, HTML & CSS

Robot OS (ROS), OpenCV, PyTorch, scikit-learn, Machine Learning, Linux, Software Dev Tools: Mercurial, Git, Jira

PCB Design (Eagle), Arduino (Uno, Due, etc.), LTSpice, Electronics Lab equipment, Soldering, RFID

Computer Vision, FPGA Lab, Robot Sensors/Actuators, ML: Deep Learning, Algorithms for Robotics, Electronics/Circuits Research (scientific/engineering), Technical and Creative writing/Proposal writing, Presentation, Teamwork, Carpentry

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Galen Robotics**

May 2018 – present Summer Internship then full-time

JHU Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics: Autonomous Systems, Control, and Optimization Lab

September 2016 – May 2018

Florida International University: School of Computing and Information Science May 2017 – August 2017

## Computer Engineer (Previously: Electrical Engineering Intern)

- Designing printed circuit boards/working on electronics for internal system and RFID hardware.
- PID tuning for smooth control of robot platform. Programming sensor-based error checks.
- Creating verification tests for electrical subsystems of robot platform.

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Installed newer components including flight control systems, guidance, and computers on drones.
- Researched and implemented motion-based teleoperation for a robotic arm attached to a drone for
  use in object manipulation. Implemented first person view teleoperation for aerial manipulation.

### Undergraduate Research Assistant at NSF/DoD Funded Research Experience for Undergraduates (REU)

- Applied advanced statistical techniques such as principal component analysis to improve hyper parameter selection for use in augmented terrain-based navigation by robots.
- Developed a method for assigning weights to water parameters while reducing correlation.
- Used these selection and weighting techniques to develop an algorithm for reducing autocorrelation to create combined parameter data maps for underwater localization.

# PROJECTS – more details and links to repositories/papers on my website (theshwin.com)

#### **Computer Vision Projects**

Augmented Webcam, Face matching

#### Robot Sensors/Actuators

Bluetooth-controlled, obstacle-avoiding car

#### FPGA Synthesis Lab

Logic Analyzer/Frequency Meter

- 1) Developed an augmented webcam experience using finger and face detection/tracking in real-time.
- 2) Implemented Siamese networks to recognize facial similarity between pairs of faces using PyTorch.

Built a small robotic car that used ultrasonic sensors to detect and avoid obstacles. Implemented a bluetooth module and programmed bluetooth control of the car to have autonomous and manual modes.

Implemented an FPGA-based logic analyzer that could be used as a USB oscilloscope/picoscope. Implemented a frequency meter that counted the frequency of inputted signals.